<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Examination answers by one of Scopes's students.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000047</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000047</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 3</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Biology Examination by Charles Storly</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Science</topic>
   </subject>
   <note>The first 1-2 pages are missing from the exam.</note>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">{Subject} Biology {Pupil} Chas. Storly{Teacher} J.T.S.\n[note: continued answer from now-missing page] then there are small [illegible] legs that appear, then [illegible] legs, he sheds his tail after wards and becomes an adult.VIIAt different ages your diet should be as required, fats portien and Charbo[illegible]es each stages requires different porpotions.A working man should have different diet from that of a man that is doing light work. and also the sex.VIIIBreathing is A automatic muscles contract and Cause air out of lungs then they relax and this Causes air to be taken into the lungs. The chest moves outward as air is taken in and goes down as air is expanding.{Subject} Biology {Pupil} Chas. StorlyIXThe sweat glands carry off waste material from the body in liquid form and also heat, they are [stricken: ne] necessary.X[note: drawing of a brain, labeled as follows]Feeling legs arm motion Thoughts smell nose mouth Balancinghearing ear. XI[note: drawing of ear, labeled as follows]internal ear.{-5}aulitory canal.middle ear.{Subject} Biology {Pupil} Chas. Storley{Teacher} J.T. Scopes.XII.Their work is to see that all laws pertaineng to health are inforced see that streets, back door or yard and all building are kepted clear of trash, dirt, and etc.XIII.Ationoids, eyestrain, bad teeth, dust, taking no exercise, not eating right kind of food proper care of themselves.XIVVaccination for fever, small pox was his {-5} greatest [work?].XV.A city disposal plant should have filterng [beds?] and should not turn their sewerage into near by streams for The next city below will get its drinking water from stream. This should never be done, it should be well filtered.{Subject} Biology {Pupil} Chas. Storley{Teacher} J.T. Scopes.\nXVIThe Jukes and Kallikak were families of theives, criminals, low breed, insane, yet a few are high minded, while other are not, they always have been around theives and inherit it so they become a theif or criminalXVII[note: drawing of cross-section of a tree, labeled as follows] Bark No years sap small holes for sap and food to pass throu pith. XVIII{-5}\n{Subject} Biology {Pupil} Chas. Storley{Teacher} J.T. Scopes.  XIX. The complete metaphosis is when a insect has got its full growth as an adult and can reproduce. an incomplete is when it is changing {-5} from one to another as from larva, pupa etc. XX.Causes [fermentation?], decay and are helpful to man in this way"Finis"</note>
</mods>
