<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Suggests Mrs. Staley go among the people to raise funds for an attorney, concludes \we must save our country.\</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000566</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000566</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 15</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from Louise B. Minor to Mrs. Staley</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Scopes, John Thomas--Trials, litigation, etc.</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">Sta. G.R.4.Memphis, TennMay 27-1925. My dear Mrs. Staley,Thank you for your letter, I am glad you wrote Mr. Bryan &amp; hope you wrote Dr. Riley. I wrote to Miss Mary Caldwell, 800 Oak St. Chattanooga, Tenn, Mr. Frank Steffens, Highland Park, Chattanooga, Tenn, to gather the people and see what could be done in way of getting a lawyer to help Mr. Bryan.Judge Dent Minor, my brother-in-law at Memphis, a lawyer for I.C.R.R. and Standard Oil connected with Mr. C.U. Burch, told me if we wanted to win that suit we should have an able lawyer to help Mr. Bryan, how about Mr. Charles Evans Hughes, ex-secretary of state, New York City? Mrs. Staley will you not take the lead among the christian people of Tenn. get a band of workers in Memphis, Chattanooga and other parts of Tenn. get money and get Mr. Hughes if you think wise or any able, [learned?] lawyer of good character? I am not known in Tenn. wife of a country Dr. and have small children, I can't leave to go among the people nor could I get large sums of money from people as I am not known, the people are against it but as yet I see no leaders in Memphis. You may write to Rev. Ben Cox, Central Baptist Church, Memphis, Tenn, Mrs. J.B. King, 70 N. [Waldren?] St Memphis, Tenn, Methodist ex-Gov. M.R. Patterson, Court House, Memphis, Tenn, [illegible]. Gov. Patterson has come out strongly against it.Mrs. Robert E. Lee 49. E. Parkway North, Memphis, Tenn. These people I know are interested.I wrote to Col. E.C. Reeves, Johnston City, Tenn. also so all the forces could be put to gather and something could be done at once. no time to delay, our enemies have realized their blunder by selecting Mr. Darrow and Malone, unbelievers and defenders of most brutal murder this country has ever known, and they are going to [stricken: sle] select a respectable lawyer now, so makes our fight the harder to win, we should gather our forces and that right away. I enclose letters I have had from Dr. Riley in regard to Mr. Charles Evans Hughes but have not heard from him, I wish you would write Mr. Bryan as how Mr. Hughes would suit, I know the people will give the money, by putting workers in Memphis and other places in Tenn. I hope you will see fit to take the lead May God bless &amp; keep you in health &amp; strength, we must save our country. Sincerely-Louise B. Minor.</note>
</mods>
