<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Handwritten report from Presbyterian ministers protesting secular articles from the Journal of Social Forces.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000125</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000125</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 5</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>"Report of the Committee appointed Febr. 16th..."</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Bible</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">Published in Charlotte Observer. Mch-2-25.Report of the COmmittee appointed Febr. 16th to write the President and Trustees of our State University - protesting against the two leading articles of the January number of the Journal of Social Forces.Your Committee has done what you instructed us to do, as shown by the attached letter, dated Febr. 18th. The attached answers to your protest, while express-ing affectionate personal esteem for you, endeavor to show that no one is responsible for the things com-plained of. The President of the University is not, for he did not see the articles. The Editor is not, for he did not write the articles. The writers are not, for they were only presenting the views of many others, gathered from a thousand sources. In spite of these disclaimers, however, we must feel that they are all responsible, for they have all taken part in the formal and official circulation of what we considered and must painfully continue to consider very insidious and poisonous opinions, rather didacti-cally expressed.(2)In addition to quotations enemurated in our letter the writers say: "God is the projection of man's better and ideal self, whom he had created and whom he thinks had created him". "The all-seeing eye of the divinity is the symbol of the social approval and disapproval manifested by group opinion." "The old notions of supernatural ethical revelations and the related view that the chief objective of right living is an entry into a heavenly paradise must be abandoned as anachronisms as antiquated and insurportable as majic, astrology and witchcraft." "The pernicious Jewish [illegible] 'naked and ashamed' has been a much damaging obstacle to both art and science and the aethetic [illegible] upon life". "The great periods of cultural effervescence have been those characterized by a large amount of freedom in sex-relations, and three of the greatest cultural degradation and decline have been accompanied with greater sex repression and purity, even including the far famed decline of the Roman empire." "Superhygiene is the only truly divine power that ever was or will be. Hence it follows that [illegible], as thus conceived, is the only true religion of the present and the future, and its' doctrines are the only true theology".(3)When such opinions are published in a magazine issued by our University, edited by a member of the faculty, and sent out to the people without a word of disclaimer on the part of the University authorities, we cannot but feel and reiterate that a serious offence has been committed against the faith and feelings and life word of the Christian people of our state.In closing this report it may be well to remind you that this matter was first called to your attention formally by a citizen of another state, the articles were discussed in open meeting and the resultant letter through us was no attack on any individual, nor persecution of any one, nor a seeking of sensational publicity; we were simply seriously and painfully disturbed by sweeping attacks upon all those doctrines and beliefs which our people have been accustomed to regard as fundamental and very precious.Having performed the duty laid upon us your committee asks to be discharged.Very Respectfully,Jno. L. CaldwellAlbert S. JohnsonA.A. McGeachyJ.M. Walker\nReport of [team?] on Journal of Social Forces.Mch 2-1925</note>
</mods>
