<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Examination answers by one of Scopes's students.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000041</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000041</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 3</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Science Examination by Traynor Hutcheson</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Science</topic>
   </subject>
   <note>The pages have been stored out of order in keeping with the archive history, but transcription was done in order as some questions carried over between pages.</note>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">IBiology Final Traynor Hutchins\nI(a) Biology is the study of plants and animals.\nII(1) is the wasp has a couple of pair of wings, covered with the hard wing's,{-2}(II) The beetle is another one 'having 2 sets of wing's the soft wing's covered with the hard[stricken: 's] ones.(III) the ant's having no wings at all,(IV)\nIII[Note: drawing of a flower with the following labeled]PestalSeples[stricken: Pollon]{-2}\nIV[Note: unlabeled drawings, likely cells]{-2}\nVThe [stricken: eno] ecnomics important of plants to man is that he gets his food from them\nVIAn Amphibia is a animal that can live in water or on land such as the frog, snake, the old frog lays her eggs in the edge of a pond, creek or some where in a warm place, and [illegible] they hatch out as tad poles and as they grow the begin to form leg's first front leg's and than begin to shed their tails and form their other leg's they get about by hoping, jumping, swiming\nVIIWhen a man is doing hard work he needs a heavierdiet, but take an old man he needs something light.\nVIIIWhen the lungs take in the air [stricken: h] the chest {-2} move in and out.\nVII continuedbut a man doing amually labor he has got to have patatoes, beans, [milk?], meat; such food to get strength out of but, a man or child, or old man need light stuff, like [stricken: e] past [illegible], toast, light food.\nIX out,{-5}\nX[Note: drawing of brain labeled as follows]MotionLegArm Face {-2}EyeMouth\n{70}{Traynor}\nXI{-5}\nXIIThe work of the city health is that they keep every thing cleaned up, have to garabe cans to keep ashes, in one and one to keep paper and stuff like that in not to mix garabe, screen the windows and put up screen doors drain off all old ponds where the mosquitoes breed, and [stricken: kee] this keep's out all filth.\nXIIISome of the deficient pupils is on the account of bad, eyes, bad ears, toncils, adinoids, and such as that, The adinoids effect their breathing through the nose and cause them to be mouth breathers. The eyes cause them to have the head ache, toncils causes them to have a bad throat cant swallow The ears effects the hearingand the [illegible] causes the [hreat?] to be bad and some times causes stomach trouble and somet[stricken: illegible]imes rhumatism.\nXIVWilliam Harry was the man that discovered how to check Small pox by Enoculation, or vacication, [I?] reckon he was the man. He was the ma[stricken: d]n that discovered these. [stricken: i] {-5}\nXVA city sewage disposal is where it empties in a river or [stricken: ocenan] ocean, or where they have a place for the disposal made first [illegible] gravel and a little coarser to the top and than large stones and turn water over this to kill [stricken: j] deases [stricken: and] germes.\nXVI\nXVII[Note: drawing of cross-section of tree trunk, labeled as follows]BArkPitHANNuALLY GROWth</note>
</mods>
