<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Handwritten letter in envelope argues against evolution from Biblical stance.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000287</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000287</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 9</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from William Dickson to J.G. McKenzie, County Judge</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <name>
      <namePart>Dickson, William</namePart>
      <role>
         <roleTerm>Creator</roleTerm>
      </role>
   </name>
   <subject>
      <topic>Scopes, John Thomas--Trials, litigation, etc.</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">June the 15 1925\nI read of A conflict between the Blind guides And [Righusness?] The Blind guides made An Asult one [Righsness?] by making [uncald?] For Remark About the virgin Mary And the creacion of Man Then thay Told Christ that is Mother And is Brothers [wants?] to see [illegible] he Ask them to [go?] to My Mother And My Brothers thay couldent Anser im he Said All those that Love god And keep is Comenent is My Mother And My Sisters And My Brothers the virgin Mary [was?] [illegible] A [illegible, three words] Bring Forth [pure?] [illegible]2And She Brought in to the World Christ Jesus the the Son of god god said that he Made the Hevns And the Earth then he Made the Animals then he Made Man After is own Emage the Blind guides clame that Man came from the Ape How Could Man Cum From the Ape when the Ape was Made Before Man the Ape is A [Best?] of the [Field?] And not Human.Christ Referens to the Blind guides he said that they would Deceive the very Elect But [By?] [thare?] works [who?] will know them.I Beleve that they Have Made a [illegible, two words] out of the Editor of the grand Forks Herald.3 this Is what he says[stricken: illegible] In is [Edarel?] on the 10 About William Scopes of Temneenesseeone of the Blind guides he said that he was selected As the persons [Apon?] [Hume?] to [Hang?] a Law Sut to test [validity?] of the teennessee Law And that is what Made A scap goat out im he [illegible] that Scopes was [illegible] For Doing what Ever other Entellegent teacher Dos And the next [Morning?] the [state?] up Famous &amp; Dont [illegible, two words] the [Editor?]Mr Scups is A Law Braker he teache [illegible] Doctrine[backed?] [By?] [illegible]4[illegible] Monkey Belefs [Moridenisum?] Mr Scope Calls tis stuff Free thought [illegible, 3 words] Made A goat out of [illegible] And it was Mad so [illegible] goats in the churches that the goats out numb the sheep to to 1Crist said I Am the Door of the Sheep Fold And he that Enters in in Aney othe way is A sheep, And A [Rober?] [illegible] put the presperiton Church on the Rocks was to [illegible] goats the prespretarns of the South wouldent give the prespeteress of the North the glad Hand And the presperion of the North wouldent give the presperrion of of the Sot the glad Hand Christ said that a House Devided Agenst It Self Cant Stand5I can see nothing But a grand [illegible] For us god is on our side the people of tennessee is on our side And The LawI [illegible] by the press that Scopes Lawres is [illegible, 3 words] And [just?] As [illegible] to [illegible] Find out that [illegible, two words] up Agins the [Laws?] [stricken: illegible] thare going to Bolt then what is going to [Become?] of Mister Scopes. No one to plead Is [cace?] thay Dont Alow in to Enter in to the Sheep Fold thay will Look on im As A [illegible] goat &amp; Shall Have to plead is case its [just?] As I say And Every Body Else says Mr Scopes is the goat sent By the so cald [illegible, two words] Know As [illegible, two words] And thay Are Like the Fellow that [illegible] [so?] there he [illegible] [Lend?] A Dog this Is the [Bunch?] that put Mr Scopes A6A Bright willing to Lern yong Man on the Rong in Every Day By is going up Agenst the Law that Ever was [illegible] And the Best people And thay Live in tennesse And the Best Law Maker And It Might Be that he Is going to [Interduce?] the Best [people?] And [Jury?][note: section torn] [illegible] Ar [Lovers?] of Free Speach Free though And Free press so Long As It Dosint Bring us on A [Level?] [illegible] Monkeys [illegible] Ar up Aginst A [illegible, two words] office Free is [illegible] [Both?] of crackers And [illegible, several words] of Free SpeachPlease send A copy of this Letter to William [illegible] [Bacon?]I Remain [illegible, two words]William DicksonEast Grand ForksMinn</note>
</mods>