<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Letter discusses immorality, murder as the result of evolutionary teaching, sends pamphlet and articles.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000332</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000332</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 10</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from H.B. King to Atty Hicks</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Bible and evolution</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">[note: text at top of first page is likely a continuation of postscript]It is not changing in the way he [wishes?].\nChicago, July 6th 25. Atty Hicks,Dayton [stricken: illegible] Tenn. Dear sir: In to-day's Chicago Daily News, Darrow announces that he has obtained the consent of Dean Shailer Mathews of Chicago University to testify at the Scopes trial This man is known the country over as the leading anti-Christian teacher, an extreme evolutionist, and in his published writings denies every essential fundamental doc[2]trine both of this old and New Testament. Only recently in an address in New York City of which I have an extract he airs his disbelief in a personal God as taught on every page of the Bible from cover to cover, but calls force God. Hence this so-called force in a cell that has evolved itself by it own inherent power, until it has finally evolved into that wonderful product a university of Chicago professor is God. John Harden in his able book on this subject quotes a number of passages from Matthews where he clearly denies every fundamental and authoritative truth of the N. testament. These men utterly the truth that 3) Christianity is a new birth instantaneously wrought by the Holy Spirit in in the spirit of man on meeting the Conditions laid down by the Lord Jesus Christ, and which changes a man's whole life, desires and tastes. Countless millions since the dawn of the Christian era have proven to a math-ematical certainy this truth of the Word of God. The un-believer, however learned in worldly wisdom is utterly in the dark here, as that very unbelief closes the door to experimental knowledge. These men now have the stupendous brazen effrontery to go on the stand to endeavor to force the public to allow them to enter the schools and4)teach this soul damning infidelity under the name of science, falsely so called. It will be easy on cross-examination with these writings before you, and an open Bible to compel them to admit their gross antagonism to every truth of the real gospel of the Word of God. This is a real bold attack on the Lord Jesus Christ Himself by these little 2 by 4 Chicago university egotists, a sample of  some of its finished product is Loeb and Leopold. Every few months in one univisty after another we have murders kidnapings &amp; suicides, and gross im-moralities. The N. Western 5)University (Methodist) of Evanton having had its two murders the [Cal.?] University and so on. Largely if not all together the result of the evolutionary teaching, and pagan philosophy imported from the Orient. The N. Western is full of this ungodly anti-Christian stuff and openly repudiates the authority of the Word of God. I am sending you under a separate cover a pamphlet by Dr. James M. Grey President of Moody Bible Institute full of meat, that you will find very interesting and valuable reading on this subject. The title "Modernism A Revolt Against Christianity A Foe to Good Government." I am also sending you a clipping of an article that admits the dishonesty practiced by the evolutionist, then winds up with some very poor stuff as [illegible] to allow them to impose this hypothetical teachings to the youthful mind. Yours in His Name for success,H.B. King,76249 Cottage Grove Ave.Chicago\nMy name will be on wrapper of pamphlet so it can readily be found among the large amount of literature you are receiving. In one of the clip-ping you will see that Mathews say that the universe is constantly changing itself, no formal God overseeing things.</note>
</mods>
