<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Examination answers by one of Scopes's students.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000042</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000042</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 3</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>General Science Examination by Bruce Kyle</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Science</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">{75}General Science Bruce Kyle\nIThe fly is a disease carier on their legs ar million of fIne hairs they light on any thing which has diseases on it then they stick to those hairs then the fly goes and light on food which man eats and have the germ so he eats the food and the germ the house fly is a bad disease cary er.\nIIThe hook worm enters the body through the feet it goes up through the blood to the lungs then it goes and fasten on to dijestic orgisms then when foods ar dijested it eats the food which the body needs. it takes a strong salution of medicine to make it turn lose,\nIIIMan place in nature the thing which he has in vented not only power but his brain man is the head in nature he has made things to protect him from injury built houses and trained wild anim als to help him cultivate he has increased the size of grain and made them so to be cultivated.\nIVIn selecting a house you should select it in good neighbor hood in a helathy place where you like good [roads?], schools, and churches, select it on a [stricken: hill] rise - not on a low place.\nVThe earth is million of years old it can be told by the mountains the form of coal and [lime?] at one which had to be formed under water by [shells?] of [muscles?], which the limestone is on mountain [illegible] and by the depth of the dirt.\nVIThe sun is bigger than the earth and is hot the earth is bigger than the moon it gets it heat from the sun the moonis the smallest it shines by the reflecting of the [stricken: sun'] sun on it. which it reflect upon the earth.\nVIIThe difference between a plannet on a true star is the true star [twinkles?] and the light from the plannet does not.\nVIIIThe back ground of the metric sistem was during the first revolution.\nIXThe determine the lengths of foot by the length of one of the King foot the yard was measured by the length of a King arm [stricken: illegible]\nX</note>
</mods>
