<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Encloses clipping with story on Darwin's supposed deathbed conversion, laments removal of the Bible from schools.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000447</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000447</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 14</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from M.W. Lusk to Messrs. Sue and Herbert Hicks</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Scopes, John Thomas--Trials, litigation, etc.</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">Los Angeles Co301, Culver St, Compton Calif, Aug 6. Gentlemen,I have been intensely interested in the great battle so nobly fought by W.J. Bryan. I read in Illustrated Daily News of Los Angeles Calif that you &amp; 2 others will carry on the battle, and I shall pray for your success.I read in the News that Mr Bryan stated that Darwin died an atheist; I know he {Mr Bryan} was truthful, so he must have been misinformed, and I thought to send him this clipping which I now forward to you. I have taken the paper it is cut from for years, &amp; believe it is thoroughly reliable, and is used of God. Lady Hope, the writer is well known in England &amp; America, as a lovely Christian character.It saddens me to know that the Bible which I have loved and read (since I was five years old, in 1855) has been taken out of the schools; and now we have to [keep?] pay teachers, whose teaching may render of none effect what the children learn of the Bible in their homes or Sunday SchoolsYours sincerely, M.W. Lusk. PS This letter is strictly private</note>
</mods>
