<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Handwritten manuscript, possibly missing pages, no authorship information, argues \not decendants of a monkey,\ cites Bible often.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000221</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000221</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 9</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>"Ye are the children of the devil Christ said..."</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Bible and evolution</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">[note: parts of this written in margins, diagonally] \nYe are the children of the devil Christ said and the works of your Father will ye do not decendants of a MonkeysIf a monkey had to do as Christ tells all in the Bible. Seek ye first the Kingdom of God and his Righteousness. Ministers Sunday school teachers would be Preaching Sermons to monkeys and sunday school teachers teaching the Bible to monkeys to make them built thair house on the sand St math 7.26 and not on a rock 7.24 ministers dont come to God St Luke 15 17 6-24 by christ dont come to christ a son of God 31.32 a Brother dont fast dont keep or teach Christs 10 commandmt dont find the straitgate And Knock st math 7.7 10th commandment all 10 is Kept in 7.7. 5,2 to 19 5²_:20 5³_:48 6-?1-4 6?-5 15.6-2?5 6-34. 6-?33 ?7-1 ?7.3.5 10th 77 ask and it God's Help Shall be given unto you) honor Christ alone and in secret, Seek and ye shall find stay here untill You do No Education needed Put your Bible away be wise Put your mind on God and seek God and love God 40 days 40 nights fast as told in St math 6 26 to 34 and starve the spirit of Mammon in mans heart. untill God gives his help and you find the devil giving you thoughts. Repent deny to do them Knock (God comes at the Knock St Luke 15:17 6-24 forgiveness of God talk with God as it tells you in the Bible to christ 31 32 )And it Shall be opened unto you church leaders dont. Knock\nEvolution is thoughts the devil in his heart gives him like he did Peter to deny Christthe devil gives man thoughts to go to church sing leis tell lies for him worship God for him be a Scribes Pharisee and Hypocrit Ye shall recive the greater damnation St math 23.Christ come to God alone and in secret the Prodigal son come to God St Luke 15-17.24 by christ and ti christ by the Father 31, 32 No church leader or member comes to God as christ I came not to send Peace but a sword the Prodigal son of God\n{Ye are the children of the Devil and the works of your Father will Ye do}Not decendants of a monkey christ was talking to Church Members Scribes and Pharisseese &amp; Scribes and Pharisseese. dont come to God St Luke 15 17 to 24 and be forgiven and received as sons and come to christ as a Brother 31-32 they go to church, follow Church leaders instead of christ, listen to sermons from false christ. who dont come to God as christ St. Luke 15,17 6-32. Brake all 10 commandments of Christ. St Math 6-5.15 Thou shalt not be like the Hypocrits 5th commandment. give 6-1-4 in secret Pray 6-5-15 in secret. fast in 6-25 34 secret overcome the devil as christ did in st math 4. false christs St math 7.15 Revive the devil sing lies tell lies for the devil. call one other christians worship God for the devil. they dont come to st Luke 15.17 to 24 And ye will not come to me St Luke 15:31 32 by the Father that ye might have life The devil gave Peter a thought to deny christ) the devil gives all men Prodigal son of God thair thoughts, untill they over come\n{If ye love me Keep my Commandments}1st St math 5:2 6-19 whosoever therefore all men. Shall Brake one of these least commandments and shall teach men so. read the rest All church leaders Brake the 10 2. 5-20 Keep all and not brake the least3 5-48 Church leaders Brake4 6-1 to 4 give in secret All 105 6-5 to 15 Pray in secret6 6-25 to 34 fast in secret over come the devil7 6.33 But seek ye first the Kingdom of God and his righteousness church leaders dont)8th 7.1 9th 7.3-5 10 7.7 all 10 is Kept in 7.7 to find the straitgate and God I am the way the truth and the life (Christ not church leaders) No man cometh to the Father but by me Ask and it Gods Help Shall be given unto you By Christ and his commandments. Seek and ye shall find (Stay here and find) Put your mind on God and seek God and love God 40 days 40 nights fast as told in 6 25 to 34 and starve the spirit of Mamm on in mans heart untill God gives his help and you find the devil giving you thoughts deny to do them Repent Knock and it shall be opened unto you. the Kingdom of God all must Seek first st math 6-33) Prodigal son of God coming to God [and?] Christ St Luke 15. 17 to 52</note>
</mods>
