<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Handwritten letter describes incompatibility of Darwinism with religion.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000111</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000111</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 4</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from H. Reinheimer "In Defence of Tennessee; Dear Sir"</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Bible and evolution</topic>
   </subject>
   <note>Date is written in day month year format.</note>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">103 King Charles RdSurbiton. 11.7.25 \nIn Defence of Tennessee.Dear Sir,I am astonished at the way in which the case of Fundamentalism is prejudged in this country. Have we lost all sense of fairness? Have we nothing but contempt for the defenders of the Christian faith? Have we really substituted Darwin for Christ? The Tennesseans may be narrow-minded and even somewhat bigoted; but, as a life-long student of the subject, I am bound to say, they are decidedly right in seeing in conventional Darwinism a foe to religion and ethics.Although Darwin was a very eminent observer, yet the philosophy of Darwinism is that of the eleventh Commandment - thou shalt not be found out. As such it is entirely wrong, as I am prepared to show.Because of its philosophy, Darwinism is incompatible with religion - and, wonderful to relate, that is apparently one reason why it is becoming so popular amongst us! Not that folks study the subject; but they know it to involve a denial of religion and of morality, and that they would seem to relish, since they desire to be entirely unshackled.Many competent biologists are coming to reject Darwin's distinctive theory, which in reality is obsolete, surviving chiefly as a cult - the most dogmatic of modern times - to which lip worship is being paid for the sake of advancement.It is not the theologians proper who are to-day inclined to revert to the methods of the inquisition. Rather it is the priests of science who exhibit that spirit. They have been careful to poison to press well in advance of the trial against the Christians of a great and friendly nation, and they would, many of them, gleefully burn a heretic at the stake if they had the power to do so.Yours faithfully,H. Reinheimer</note>
</mods>
