<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Repeats desire to have manuscript published in Tennessee, expresses regret over Bryan's death.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000389</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000389</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 11</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from S.L. Walters to H.E. Hicks</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Scopes, John Thomas--Trials, litigation, etc.</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">4851 Broadway Chicago Ill. Aug 17th 1925. Mr. H.E. Hicks,Dayton Tenn. Not having a reply to my letter which made known to you, my desire to have your assistance in the publishing of the m.ss. and to have it done in Tenn.as I believe you have some very good Pub. Houses in your. State. i trust that you will take an interest in the work. Will say that in addition to knowing the value of my work, I have several people who are well versed in the Occult forces, and who are able to go deep into the Study. They have repeatedly told me that my work would spread through out the civilized world. in a year or two. and where ever my work is published, that is: this first work, they will then get the following work. I believe that I told you I wanted it to go under royalty by all means, because it will be a work that will be published for ages to come. My plans are to Will the Royaltys to the Nation or State that it is published in. And will add, that in case you decide to aid me, I do not want my whereabouts known. Though I want my Book Published in my full name. Then I will move to a strange part of the city an take another name. I do not want to meet the press, reporters.I am just heartbroken over Mr Bryans Death.I had counted so much on helping him. He was a Christly man, as well as being a Christ Student he surely did know the works of Christ, and the Testement. He was a great man, a man who the whole world will miss, in the comming years and I will tell you the same as I tell the people in Chicago. That during the argument which he had with that monster Dragon Darrow. ,He, Mr Bryan had a Stroke which made him all but loose consciousness. I knew before the trial, there would be something, going to happen. And the moment, that I layed eys on that one picture of Bryan. I knew that he, had, had a stroke, as well as the little message which told me he had a stroke, and that death was very near him. Wonderfully brave man, to do all he did, after knowing what he knew. That the end was near. For he had had the call, that he was wanted in a greater place. Though it is not known that he had a stroke and he did not want to cause his wife any wory. He knew something happened to his head:someday I hope to come out in his defence, and tell just what came to me. And how the papers abused him. (I say.) Shame to the, some day I want them to get what is comming to them.Trusting I am not imposing on you, and that you will be able to aid in bringing my work before the public.Respectfully Yours, S.L. Walters</note>
</mods>
