<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Letter of support for Bryan and the trial, expresses interest in corresponding with Bryan on spiritual matters.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000308</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000308</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 10</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from Lavada J. Young to William J. Bryan</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Scopes, John Thomas--Trials, litigation, etc.</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">Miss Lavada J. Young,Nelsonville, OhioR.F.W. #3. Nelsonville, Ohio,July 4, 1925. Mr. William J. Bryan, Dear sir: Although I am only a 22-year old country girl with only a common school education, I am deeply interested in the great cause for which I believe you are working. And because of this I am taking the liberty to write you just to let you know that I am on your side, and I believe the spirit of the fields is with you also.I do not believe that you are against education. Any man or woman of ordinary intelligence knows that we need education. But I believe that many of our educated people of today are becoming the victimsof overestimated enthusiasm. Christ gave His life to save the weak, not the strong, and when He left the earth He left us in charge. I believe that we have reached the time when someone must call a halt, or see these people who are smitten with overstimulated enthusiasm weaken the bridge upon which millions of weak mortals must cross, and see the happiness of earthly man become forever lost in the chaos of oblivion, for happiness can never come to bless those who have become exalted, but is found in the beautiful simplicity of common things.In the teaching of evolution so far back as the education of man, I can see nothing to gain but much to lose. And while it is well that we continue the building of our civilization, it is also well that we consider how we are going to save that which has already been built, for to wreck the weak man's faith in God is to place our country beneath the burden of crime, immorality, graft, corrupted society beneath a covering of polish and artificial refinement, disregard for the laws of Nature and a total loss of love for the right.In this day of advanced civilization we must end war. But to wreck the weak man's faith in God is to scatter the germs of war over all the world. Therefore, I believe it to be the duty of every true American to have courage enough - without the fear of losing their position in the world - to come forward and battle against those theories which will have a tendency to create evil influences in the mind of the child who has not yet had the experience like the experience of Christ, lest some of us become exalted, crush the remaining hopes of suffering humanity, and make civilization a curse to the world. After this trial in Tennessee I should like to hear from you, as I have written my ideas on life, and the Bible, and, if you should think that you would have the patience to read the works of so rank an amateur, I would be greatly pleased to send it to you.While I write a fly, because of a curiosity to solve something which was altogether unnecessary, has become lost in the contents of my ink bottle - which reminds me of the foolishness of many who belong to the human race.Solomon says, "And further, by these, my son, be admonished: of making many books there is no end, and much study is a weariness of the flesh."Let us hear the conclusion of the whole matter: Fear God, and keep his commandments: for this is the whole duty of man." Ecclesiastes; 12: 12-13.Show them the spirit in which our forefathers laid the foundation of our glorious nation and let them know that the brave missionaries have not given their lives in foreign fields in vain.May this letter help you in any way that it can.Wishing for your victory and the future welfare of the human race, I am,Yours respectfully,Lavada J. Young.P.S. "J." must mean jug. And if it does it must contain the same spirits that won the battle of Yorktown.L.J. Young.</note>
</mods>
