<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Anti-evolution sentiment, postscript praising Austin Peay.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000301</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000301</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 9</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from Alexander Spotswood Dandridge to Prosecuting Attorney</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Scopes, John Thomas--Trials, litigation, etc.</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">[note: postscript is written vertically up the left side of the page]\nWinchester Virginia,June 28th 1925. Prosecuting Attorney Dayton Tennessee,My Dear Sir If those so-called scientific agnostics from [stricken: Chicago?] the East and The West want to air their [Atheistic?] doctorine to the extent that the animal (Monkey) had any origin or connection in the creation of man then invite them to leave Tennessee.[stricken: God will] Tennesseans look to their Creator &amp; Merciful Redeemer not to these so-called scientific [tramps?].God created man in His own image - here is where the real man-looking monkey (the Ape) came from - some South Asiatic or African man eater or cannable married a she monkey even without a dog [license?] and produced the ape. If a man is born with only one leg or 5 legs this is a freak of Nature, caused by the sin of man on his children. Evolution is Hellward - [illegible] man going into the beast. Evolution is confined  within the developement of its Kind- we reap the seed we sow.Yours sincerely, Alexander Spotswood Dandridge civic Engineer.P.S. You have a Governor of the right ring. he had within him the right proper spirit when he says this Nation [wants?] to the God &amp; this school. 3 cheers for Governor Austin Peay.</note>
</mods>
