<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Letter from unknown party describes questioning Leopold and Loeb as to their views on religion and evolution.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000092</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000092</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 4</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>"On the second of August, '24 it was my privilege..."</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Bible and evolution</topic>
   </subject>
   <note>Written on the reverse of election ballots; some scorch marks.</note>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">1.On the second of August, '24 it was my privilege, through the kindness of Mr. Money-penny, Warden of the Cook Co. jail, to interview the daring criminals, Leopold and Loeb, on their religious be-liefs; and particularly with reference to the relation of the doctrine of evolution as taught in Chicago University, and their [consequent?] philosophy of life. Most of the answers to my questions were given by Leopold, Loeb nodding affirmation to his pals view when I repeated what Leopold had said, in answer to my questions. (2.) After the preliminaries of explanation as to the occasion of my visit, I said, "Do you believe in evolution?" He replied, "I most certainly do; all sane people believe in evolution." [note: some of the following was later underlined.] "What theory of evolution do you hold?" He said, "I believe in Orthogenesis." "And what is your conception of Orthogenesis?""Well, it is the very latest theory of evolution - later than the Darwin[illegible], Lamarckian or the Freudian.""Is there any room for God in your theory?""Absolutely no," he said with emphasis, quickly adding, "You must be a follower of (3.)William Jennings Bryan". I replied - [stricken: "I did] "I do not claim to be a follower of any one but the Lord Jesus Christ, and a very poor one at that, but as between Mr. Bryan and his critics my sympathies are de-cidedly with Mr. Bryan." He grew quite animated at once and scoffed back: "Well pardon me for insult-ing a friend, but I think William Jennings Bryan is the biggest fool ever turned loose in America on the evolutionary question." I then utilized my remaining lim-ited time by expressing my profound conviction (4.)that the sad predicament in which he found him-self was the direct [fruit?], of which his evolutionary beliefs were the root, and submitted to their consider-ation the little book en-titled "The reason why" which both boys promised me faithfully they would read. That afternoon while some students from Michigan and Chicago Universities where testifying, an inter-ested listener who sat be-side me behind Judge Caverly's desk, as he had kindly invited us to seat there where we could hear [more?] readily, remarked to me(5.) that he had taught Loeb in the department of Psychol-ogy, in which he served as an Assistant Professor. I then expressed to him my delight of the privilege of meeting him, recounted my conversation with the boys as recorded a-bove, and asked if they had correctly reported that teaching of the University. He replied that they had, and I further asked if in his judgment there views were shared by the teachers of science in the University and he as-sured me they were, and also shared by himself.(6.)Amongst the details of my questioning of Leo-pold that I recall, was the question whether he considered we are direct descendants from mon-keys; he replied "oh no, that is not scientific; the correct and latest sci-entific view is that both man and monkey are descended from the same source which is now be-ing sought and commonly known as the "missing link". I further asked "what then he considered [our?] relation-[illegible: shi?]p to the monkey to be?" He replied "I would say we are distant cousins." I repeated this to the [stricken: C of] U of C Professor(7.)and asked if the young men were scientifically ac-curate in this view and he said "quite so", but added that he wouldn't say Mr. L. was correct in say-ing Orthogenesis was the very latest evolutionary theory and left me with the impression that the whole question is in such a nebulous state from the scientific standpoint that no man could claim the right to state dog-matically that any par-ticular theory is "the very latest."</note>
</mods>
