<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Religious theory on miscegenation and the development of Israel.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000333</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000333</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 10</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from G.W. Pratt to Prosecuting Attorney On The Scopes Ape Trial</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Bible and evolution</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">Remember It Would Of Been a Dishonor to Abraham If the Lord Had of made the Gentiles any thing Less than Hebrews.\nThe Lord Is Exalted. Prosecuting Attorney In The Scopes Ape Trial. Dear Sir, I Appeal to your Excellency In Reference To Mr. Scopes His understanding Is Choked On The Blindness Of Isreal å¦ Abraham Was a Gentile Before The Lord Blessed Him and made Him a Hebrew. So Abraham Was The Remote Ancestor Of the Hebrew Race. For The Blood Of the[2] Covenant Was In Him. That,s Why The Lord,s Hands Was Stretched Out To Isreal Before Jesus Was Crucified and Isreal Would not. The Reason The Lord Was So Lenient To Isreal Was Because They Had The Blood Of Abraham In Them. å¦ The Gentiles Were to Be Grafted Into Isreal Because Abraham Was First a Gentile you can understand that By Reading the[3]Eleventh Chapter of Romans Especially the 28-verseå¦The Lord Says He Will Bring Isreal again you Can understand It Will Be through the Gentileså¦Remember I dont mean the negroes are Gentiles. I dont mean The malays are gentiles and the Like. If all Other Races Were to Be Grafted Into Isreal By nature The Scopes [4] Case Would not Be On Hand. For Isreal Would Have Plenty of Ro[om To Expand.å¦ you Can understand The Races the Lord made to Dishonor He never Intended them As Rulers and Leaders\nI Will Take up the Ape trial The Lord never made The Life Of Apes and So On Of the Holy Spirit But He made the Life Apes and So on [5] Of The [illegible] Spirits and not the Holy Spirit. that He made The Soul Of man Of The Holy Spirit Is Sacred For man Is the only Being Required to marry For the Life Of the Soul Is In the Replenishing nature Of Life As Life of Eve Soul Was On the Rib taken From Adam,s Side.  The Ape can not Conceive the Thoughts Of the Holy Spirit[6] If He could He could make an Airplane, Build Locomotives make Clocks and Watches and Automobiles and So On and So On. The Ape and the Like and So on Can Conceive the Thoughts Of the Spirit to Which they Belong But they Sure Dont Belong to the Holy Spirit that the Soul of man Belongs to[7]The Potter made vessels of the Same Lump to Honor and Some to Dishonor So The Lord made The Races. Where Isreal Is mingled With The Dishonored Races They are known In the Scriptures as The mingled People With you. Have you Ever Gave a Serious Thought about Abraham Offering up Isaac On the Altar of Sacrifice. It Seems It Was almost as Hard as It Was With Jesus In the Garden Of Gethsemane night Before He Was Crucified next day[8] Dont think It Was a myth about Abraham and the angel Speaking Out of Heaven to Him For the Tabernacle of the Lord Was Standing With Abraham then. Later on the Lord called It the Tabernacle Of David In Honor of David. When Jesus Was Crucified the veil In the Temple Was Rent and the Tabernacle Of David Fell Down to All Except those that Belonged to the State of Apostleship It Was necessary For them to Have the Benefit of It to Finish Writing the Bible  The Substitute Given to the [9] Gentiles Is Equivalent Only to the Simple Past Of the Tabernacle of David. For the Angels Dont Come Down now Like they Did When the Tabernacle Was Standing. you can understand the Gentiles Could not Entertain Angels By Having to Send After Peter that Was Because they Did not Have the Blood of the Covenant In them that Was Why the Lord Scattered the Little Remnant Of the Lost Tribes of Isreal Among the Gentiles So they marry and [10] mingle the Blood With the Gentiles So When The Lord Brings Isreal again It Will Be Through the Gentiles. The 60 chapter 16 verse of Isaiah they Shall Suck the milk Of the Gentiles and Shalt Suck the Breast Of Kings. that Is the Kings Own Children For they Will Be mingles With Isreal This Last Paragraph the Tabernacle Of David Will Be Standing then. I cant tell How Long It Will Be until then, But the Way the World Is Developed[11]It Seems It Is not Far Distant. They tell me the Jews Is Building a temple at Jerusalem now. The Outer Court John Was told to Leave Out and measure not For It Is Given to the Gentiles. I understand When the Lord Puts that Court Back Like It Was When the Tabernacle of David Was Standing then He Will Send His Angels Down and uncover the Dark understanding of the Jews and Rebuild the Tabernacle of David [12] The Lord Has mingles the Little Remnant Of Benjamin and the other 10 Lost Tribes Of Isreal With the Gentiles and made the Gentiles Hebrews as He the Lord made Abraham a Hebrew. you can understand It Would Of Been a Dishonors For The Lord to Of made the Gentiles anything Less than Hebrews. that Is It Would Of Been a Dishonor to Abraham For the Gentiles was the Honored Race [13] The Gentiles Is the main Center Of the House Of Isreal For All Of them Has a Little Of the Hebrew Blood. Some Of them Looks to Be Full Blood those that Favor the Gentiles may be Whole Brother or Sister to those that Favors Abraham there Remote Ancestor. yours Respectfully,G.W. Pratt.Rockingham NC R 4 Box 38 at midway  July th 6 1925-</note>
</mods>
