<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Expresses gratitude, incloses money for return of manuscript, discusses current work.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000417</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000417</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 13</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from S.L. Walters to Hicks &amp; Hicks</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Evolution (Biology)--Religious aspects--Christianity</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">4851 BroadwayChicago Ill. March 5 1927. Hicks and Hicks Dayton Tenn. Gentleman, Some what late in writing you immediatily after receiving yours of Aug 24 went to the Hospital, and was not able to attend to my affairs. I sure was thankful to hear from you, was not worried about your honesty, will be honest and tell you the cause of my worry. I felt that your firm was not going to remain in Dayton, such a very long time, however I was indeed glad to get your letter, am writing you now asking you to send m.s.s to the accompanying Address will inclose $1.00 for postage. Send by Parcel Post. will also inform you about my work that I am now doing. I now feel there is no doubt but that I have proved evolution, which will be a great surprise to the many people who think they have solved the problem. there is such a thing as evolution, but never never the idea that Science teaches, which is a terriable thing. That men so wonderful as the men of Science are, And to stumble over such wonderful matter than any thinking man could hardly pass over. you your selves can take the problem of Gen. 3-15. Thy Seed, and her seed. I ask you just follow Reff.. leading out from Thy Seed. In one half hour, you have the problem. all you have to do is to Search the proof. I am told the work which I am on now will appall the Nation when they awaken to its true meaning. Am going now to try to have the work which you have, published in Serial. Am holding my work away from eastern Publishers, not meaning to be confidential. I am not able to have it published in book form, here in Chicago they want twenty five hundred dollars, and I have not got it. I have a Lawyer, here who has advised me of a way to get my work started, though I do not worry now it is bound to go there. And I feel sure it will be on the market this year. I am very thankful to you, in taking care of my work, will tell you why I have left it with you so long, it is simply through fear of having it stolen my house has been broken open twice to get that work, and I hope and trust that you will help me with your influence. Thanking you for your kindness and trusting you will at an early date send mss. to me, will at some future date remember your kindness. Sincerly yoursS L Walters</note>
</mods>
