<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Discusses counsel for trial, offers to raise money to hire additional attorney, expresses concerns for Bryan.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000564</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000564</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 15</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from Mrs. L.L. Minor to Dr. Riley</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Scopes, John Thomas--Trials, litigation, etc.</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">May 18. 1925. Dear Dr. Riley -My husband, Dr. Minor, has a brother, Judge H. Dent Minor, assistant general solicitor of J.C. [Milrod?] also attorney for Standard Oil and a man of legal ability. Judge Minor suggested to me that if we wanted to win that suit at Dayton, Tenn. we had beter have a good lawyer to keep Mr. Bryan and Mr. Thompson the Tenn. attorney as Mr. Bryan, while a brilliant man and able lawyer but he has so many things on his mind all the time, and [illegible] be too heavy a load for him and Mr. Darrow a brilliant lawyer, but an atheist will trap him in some-2-points that Mr. Bryan has possibly overlooked, in other words Mr. Bryan will need a fine legal mind to help, besides Mr. Thompson of Tenn. [Now?] Dr. Riley I have a diamond engagement ring and a little land I will sell or mortgage to raise money to putt a fine Christian lawyer to help Mr. Bryan &amp; Mr. Thompson if you want it; I have two children to educate, but all [illegible] lay on the altar for the cause of Christ. Judge Minor has spent all his life in study and knows very little about the church and evolution, and is not concerned either for or against evolution, but -3-gave me that advice unsolicited yesterday. Dr. R.A. Meek, editor of the Southern Methodist, knows us quite well also Judge Minor, and is a member of our church.Mr. Bryan will bring the whole country to Dayton as the people are for him and please Dr. Riley get the great preachers as you had in Memphis and scholars of our colleges and you all come and stay in Dayton and give evolution a terrific blow in Tenn. at that trial. Senator Leroy Percy of Miss. told Judge Minor if Mr.4Bryan would go to that trial you could not get in 3 miles of the court house, that is one reason we want an able lawyer to help Mr. Bryan. Please look on this country and select an able Christian lawyer to give his time to that trial. Judge Minor says the fact that Mr. Darrow has been accepted by the evolutionist will be a big blow to their following, as Mr. Darrow you know is an atheist and a defender of a most brutal crime the sentiment of the country is against Mr. Darrow. I hope Mr. Bryan will [illegible, two words] over the country.I think the south is getting up from their slum-{over} 5ber after that great meeting you great men held in Memphis. Enclose [find?] clipping. mr. Major suggests Mr. Walker D. Hines, 24 [Broad?] St. New York City, but I would advise you to look into this man as to his views on evolution and character. You are our leader gather your forces, college prof. preachers, and lawyers, and I know the people if they [illegible] of it will furnish the money. With our prayers always. Pray for Mr. Bryan long may he live and go up &amp; down the land [illegible] the people. Most Cordially,Mrs. L.L. Minor\n{Ex-Gov. M. R. Patterson would make a good lawyer. Court House, Memphis, Tenn.}\nI send $1.00 in money order, please send me that many leaflets, "Christian Funddametal in Schools-Church." If you have none of these phamplets send me something on evolution that I may give out to people in other states.Mrs. Minor</note>
</mods>
