<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mods xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3"
      xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
      xmlns:xs="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema"
      xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.loc.gov/mods/v3 http://www.loc.gov/standards/mods/v3/mods-3-5.xsd">
   <abstract>Suggests books on the subject of the incompatibility of evolution with Christianity, dismisses Darrow and scientists.</abstract>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Collection" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Sue K. Hicks Papers</title>
      </titleInfo>
      <identifier>MPA.0136</identifier>
   </relatedItem>
   <relatedItem displayLabel="Project" type="host">
      <titleInfo>
         <title>Of Monkeys and Men: Public and Private Views from the Scopes Trial</title>
      </titleInfo>
   </relatedItem>
   <identifier type="filename">0012_000416_000433</identifier>
   <language>
      <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
   </language>
   <recordInfo>
      <recordIdentifier>record_0012_000416_000433</recordIdentifier>
      <recordContentSource>University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Libraries</recordContentSource>
      <languageOfCataloging>
         <languageTerm type="code" authority="iso639-2b">eng</languageTerm>
      </languageOfCataloging>
      <recordOrigin>Created and edited in general conformance to MODS Guidelines (Version 3.5).</recordOrigin>
   </recordInfo>
   <location>
      <physicalLocation>University of Tennessee, Knoxville.  Special Collections</physicalLocation>
      <holdingSimple>
         <copyInformation>
            <shelfLocator>Box 5, Folder 14</shelfLocator>
         </copyInformation>
      </holdingSimple>
   </location>
   <titleInfo>
      <title>Letter from H.B. King to Atty's Hicks</title>
   </titleInfo>
   <subject>
      <topic>Bible and evolution</topic>
   </subject>
   <accessCondition>The copyright interests in this item remain with the creator. For more information contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.</accessCondition>
   <note displayLabel="Transcription">[marginal note likely continued postscript]Price has exposed in "Back to the Bible" the "[illegible] [stricken: skin?] [coral?]" theory on which a vast amount of false geological data has been founded and taught.\nChicago, Ill. July 1st 25\nAtty's HicksDayton, Tenn.My dear sirs. Please pardon the intrusion of your time with this letter; but I am deeply interested with the success of the prosecution of the Scopes case. You no doubt are pretty well aupplied with books and other literature exposing the false science called evolution, but I do not believe you can have too many in view of the announcement of the defense att'y that they intend to put noted men on the stand to substantiate the claims of evoulution and to prove that it is not [stricken: a] antagonistic to Christianity, hence2)I wish to suggest some books that you may not have.1) "The Absurdities of Evolution" on sale at Moody Bible institute Book Store 153 Institute Place, Chicago IllThis is one of the completest exposures of this false stuff and showing up the dishonesty of many of its advocates and the frauds they have practiced on the public in certain [pride?] of human bones. The author is very familiar with the subject and amply able to cope with any evolutionist. It would be of extraordinay value in the hands of the lawyer, when he comes to cross-examine the defenses experts. You will find it in simple language, and rich reading.2) A very able booklet by L.T. Townsend great, scholar and writer3.) 2. "The Collapse of Evolution" {10å¢}3. "Modern Education at the Cross Roads. {10å¢} by former Yale professor. A magnificent article showing the awful effect of evolution in the schools.4. A very able book by the able lawyer, Phillip Mauro of Washington D.C. a noted Christian writer and thoroughly familiar with the subject of evolution and the other false philosophies now being taught in modern Universities. A highly educated man who spent many years studying these false systems, prior to his being converted and becoming a Christian "Evolution at the Bar"Bible Tuth DepotSwengel Pa.Another of his latest works, "The Chronology of the Bible" of great valu [stricken: Cl?] Darrow the agnostic is totally ignorant of real Christianity, which is a new birth. He is also not a scientist and knows scarcely no-thing of the teachings of evolution likewise Malone. Had they been real Christians or real scientiss the would never make the ludricus blunder of putting noted evolutionist on the stand. Most of their listed witnesses it will be found on cross-examination were never born again, St. John 3d chap. and therefore have no vital experimental knowledge of Christianity, that is why they are antagonistic to nearly all the fundamental principles of tha Bible. What a glorious chance for a real Christian lawyer who thoroughly knows his Bible and also knows the so-called science of evolution, to com-pletely expose the whole rotten [5] stuff and at the same time thorouoghly expose there scholar-ship and bogus Christianity. It will be easy to hold up the whole false theory, and compel them out of their own mouths to show that evolution is thoroughly and wholly antagonistic and diametrically opposite to the Bible and real Christianity. Have no fears of Darrow, he is greatly overrated, and while a fairly good hand to try a murder case he is clear out of his element in this case, and in water way over his head where he can't swim, like-wise Malone + Colby, although the last named and undoubtedly the ablest would be of some account on the constitutional side of the question in the Supreme Court. So far as I know he also is practically un-versed in evolution, and the Bible. The daily press do not reflect the the opinions of the real people, but are filled full of false propaganda on the evolution stuff. Millions upon millions of hearts are with the prosecution side, and are wishing you every success.Resp'ly yours. W.B. King6249 Cottage Grove ave, Chicago. P.S. In the defense list of witnesses are a number of geologist, one and old friend of my boyhood days. Prof. Geo. McCready Price the eminent geologist has exposed the many [illegible] now being taught as facts of geology, in his books "Back to the Bible" is one of his best.</note>
</mods>
